Ing. Roman Ožana / Resume

Hi there,

my name is Roman Ožana. I am a freelance webdesigner and developer with **more than 9 years of experiences**. I'm here to create websites and applications easy to use, intuitive and modern inside. I love tech startups and community around. Enjoy working in small and effective team.

Say hi on Twitter @OzzyCzech

• Address: Prague, Přímětická st.

Web: <u>www.omdesign.cz</u>
Email: <u>ozana@omdesign.cz</u>
Phone: <u>+420 605 783 455</u>



Working Experiences

<u>Testomato s.r.o.</u> – Co-founder & main developer

March 2012 – present

Devel.cz Lab s.r.o. - PHP/JS developer

October 2009 – present

Work as PHP/JS developer and web designer mostly on zdrojak.cz

omdesign.cz - Freelance web designer

October 2009 – present

Freelance web designer and developer of Internet application – mostly in PHP/Javascript.

6 years 5 months 1 day

7 years 3 months 1 day

9 years 6 months 2 days

Former Working Experiences

Intergraph s.r.o. - Application Engineer

July 2010 - April 2011

Application Engineer (external consultant) – testing of corporate solution for metadata sharing and managing. Developing of simple C# .NET applications.

Skvely.CZ s.r.o. - PHP developer

March 2009 - July 2010

Works there as web application developer mostly in PHP and developing some modules for e-commerce Magento.

9 months

1 year 5 months

Skills & Technologies

Day-to-day comfort

- PHP (up to 7.x)
- · OOP, DI, IOC, design patterns
- SQL language (MariaDB, MySQL)
- · MySQL, Redis, MongoDB, Memcached
- Javascript
- · Angular, jQuery
- HTML5, CSS3 (incl. LESS, Sass, cssnext, PostCSS)
- Webpack 4 & Makefile
- · Responsive Layout and Design
- · Basics of Photoshop and Adobe Illustrator

Quality assurance

- E2E testing with Protractor
- Selenium + Selenium IDE
- Unit Testing (PHP Unit, Nette Tester, Mocha)

Experience with

- · React, NextJS
- Node.js
- · Gulp & Grunt
- Couchbase

DevStack

- Docker
- · Git version control
- · Webpack, Makefile
- Travis & GitLab CI
- MacOS and Linux

Languages

- Czech native language
- English communicative

Additional Info

· Driving license: B

Education

VŠB - Technical University of Ostrava

2002 - 2007: Geoinformatics

- Study program: Geodesy and cartography, Geoinformatics
- Degree: Master's degree (Msc., Geoingormatics)
- Address: VŠB Technical university of Ostrava, 17.listopadu 15, Ostrava Poruba, Faculty of Mining and Geology

SPŠE Rožnov pod Radhoštěm

1997 – 2001: Electronic computer systems

GitHub: https://github.com/OzzyCzech/

StackOverflow: https://meta.stackoverflow.com/users/355316/

Twitter: https://www.twitter.com/OzzyCzech